#Encodergasm Presents
～
Confirmed.
（カルロス）確かに
To our new relationship, and our new friendship.
（マオ）新たな関係と友情を祝って
And to prosperity.
（カルロス）
そしてお互いの繁栄を願って
The view from here makes me sad that I must leave so soon.
すぐに 発たたねばならないのが
残念ですよ
It's an amazing sight.
ここからの眺めは素晴らしい
Next time, we should have dinner together.
この次は ご一緒に食事でも
The Cantonese cuisine that our head chef makes...
うちの料理長が作る広東料理は―
...is just about as superb as this scenery.
景色に勝るとも
劣らないものでしてね
That's a wonderful invitation, however...
（カルロス）
それは うれしいお誘いですな
しかし―
To think that the day that I'd dine with an executive from the Red Dragon...
レッド･ドラゴンの幹部と
食事をする日が来ようとは
毒は入っていませんから ご安心を
Rest assured, the food will not be poisoned.
I can finally take a breather.
これで一息つけるな　やれやれだ
Thank God.
（マオ）こんなことをしても
何にもならんぞ
Doing things like this won't do you any good!
Times have changed!
時代は変わったんだ
今どき 抗争ばかりで
組織が生き残れるか
The syndicate cannot survive just by fighting alone!
O-Only if...
うっ ス スパイクさえ戻れば―
...S-Spike returned...
...someone like you would...
お前など…
（ジェット）気が進まねえな
I don't feel up for this.
What?
（スパイク）あん？
I said, I don't feel like doing this.
乗り気じゃねえって言ってんだよ
Then there's no choice.
（スパイク）なら仕方ねえな
Wait, Spike.
待てよ スパイク
I can't burden you.
（スパイク）迷惑は掛けねえよ
Don't say stuff like that.
んなこと言ってんじゃねえ
あれが何者か知ってんのか？
You know who that is, don't you?
Superficial stuff, yeah.
（スパイク）一通りはな
Then...
（ジェット）なら…
Good money.  Easy to get info on him.
（スパイク）賞金もいい
情報も集めやすい　心当たりもある
We also have a lead.
What makes you scared?
何をおじけづく？
Spike, you're deliberately avoiding the subject.
（ジェット）スパイク
お前 話をわざとそらしてるぜ
Are you hiding something from me?
隠してることでもあるのか？
あんたのその腕 どうしたよ
So... what happened to that arm of yours?
何の関係がある？
What does that have to do with anything?
Nothing.
ないな
So, you have no intention of telling me?
（ジェット）
言う気はないってことか
お互いにな
I could ask you the same.
（フェイ）ああー このドア
なんでこんなに狭いわけ？
Why is this door so damn narrow?
（フェイ）あっ うん？
あーら お邪魔？
Oh?  Am I interrupting something?
（ジェット）お前には関係ねえ
None of your business.
えー？ 仲間だってのに冷たーい
We're supposed to be comrades!  That's awfully cold of you!
What do you mean, comrades?
何が仲間だ
厄介者が首を突っ込むな
Troublemakers should keep themselves out of this.
（フェイ）
ふーん　ま いいけどね
Well, I don't care.
フッ… っと
So, who is this?  What's he up to?
こいつ誰？ なにもん？
Don't look without asking us.
勝手に見るな
What do you mean?  He's just there on the screen!
（フェイ）何よ
勝手に映ってたんじゃない
スパイク！
Spike!
Hey, wait, Spike!
おい 待てよ！ スパイク
発進する
I'm taking off.
Spike!
（ジェット）スパイク！
くそ！ 俺は知らねえからな
Shit, I won't be responsible for you!
（スパイク）了解
Roger that.
（ジェット）ちっ
Dammit!  He's such a...
あいつ…
マオ･イェンライ
Mao Yenrai.
A bounty of 28 million for the alleged murder...
敵対組織幹部の殺人容疑で
2800万の賞金
...of an executive from an opposing syndicate.
Amazing!  And you guys are after him?
すごーい　これ狙ってるわけ？
ん 何？ ケンカしたの？
What, did you have a fight?
Shut up.  You're being obnoxious.
（ジェット）黙れ　うるさい
フッ 子供
You're such a kid.
I said, you're being obnoxious!
（ジェット）うるせえってんだよ
He can do whatever the hell he pleases.
勝手にするがいいさ
やーだ やだ　大荒れ
Oh, God...  He's throwing such a huge fit.
You there, Jet?  I got something big for ya!
いるか？ ジェット
でかいネタがある
でかいネタ
Something big?
（係員）お客さま 恐れ入ります
Excuse me, madam, but I need to see your ticket.
チケットを
拝見させていただけますか？
あら そんなもの持ってないわ
Oh, I don't have anything like that.
Well, then, I am afraid that you cannot enter the hall...
ああ それですと
恐れ入りますがご入場は…
But, they told me I didn't need one.
だって 必要ないって
言われたんですもの
知ってるでしょ？
ボックス席の あのお方よ
You know.  The guy in the box seat...
HIM.
マオ･イェンラ…
Mao Yen-
車 回しといてくださる？ フフッ
Can you park my vehicle for me?
If it's not one, it's the other...
（ジェット）どいつも こいつも
勝手なまねばかりしやがる
Why do they all do everything as they please?!
ん？ プロテクトがかかってるな
There's a protective encryption on this thing.
（ジェット）うん？ 心配か？
You worried?
Just watch.  These are decrypted like this...
まあ 見てな
こういうのは こうやって…
See?  And then, I input "Mao Yenrai"...
なあっ？ それで
マオ･イェンライと
The bounty part sure seems to be true, but...
賞金が懸かってんのは
さすがにガセじゃなさそうだが
Is this Mao-taijin's seat?
（フェイ）
マオ大人(たいじん)のお席は こちら？
I looked all over for it.  Actually, I...
探しちゃったわ　実は私…
お待ちしておりました
We were waiting for you.
えっ？ あ あの…
U-Um...
（フェイ）うっ…
They are performing, so please stay quiet.
上演中ですので どうかお静かに
うししし
（アニー）待ちな！
（子供たち）うっ
Hold it right there!
（アニー）逃がさないよ
I'm not letting you get away!
Whatcha doin'?!
何すんだよ！
Give it back!
返せ！ くそっ 返せ　この野郎
Shit.  Give it back, you dumbass!
うわっ！ イテッ うっ
Really, kids these days!
（アニー）
全く このガキどもときたら
警察に突き出してやる
（子供たち）離せよ
この野郎
I'll hand you over to the cops!
ああっ あんた
Y-You!
Yo.
いひひ
（アニー）はぁっ…
おい 一気に飲んじゃ
体に悪いだろ アニー
Hey, isn't it bad for you to drink it in one shot, Annie?
あんたが
よみがえってきたことのほうが―
You coming back to life is worse on me than this glass.
よっぽど体に悪いよ
ひでえ言われようだな
What terrible treatment!
ふん 死人が何 言っても無駄だよ
The words of the dead are meaningless.
But I'm alive.
生きてるって
No, you died three years ago!  That's how things work here.
あんたは３年前に死んだの
そういうことになってんだから
（アニー）分かってるよ
I know.
The fact that you came here... means you have something you want to know, right?
あんたがうちに来たってことは
知りたいことがあるんだろ？
少しぐらいなら力になってやるよ
If it's not much, I can be of help.
Anastasia...
アナスタシア
Stop it!  There are only two people that can call me by that name...
（アニー）よしな！
あたしをその名前で呼んでいいのは
２人しか いないんだから
So, what do you want to know?
で 何が知りたいってんだい？
Mao Yenrai.
（スパイク）マオ･イェンライ
何があった？
What happened to him?
Mao-taijin?  There's a reason for this...
（フェイ）マオ大人？
これには訳が…
No need to talk, Miss Valentine.
（護衛）お話は結構です
ミス･ヴァレンタイン
（フェイ）あっ
We have done a background check already.
既に調べさせていただきましたので
Rest assured, it will be held in a safe location.
ご心配なく
大切に預からせていただきます
Please, to your seat.
どうぞ お席へ
You're trembling...
（ビシャス）震えているな
あんた―
Who... are you?
誰？
ビシャス
Vicious.
（アニー）なあ
You know...
悪いことは言わない
I won't say anything bad to you.
Don't get yourself involved with Vicious anymore.
もう ビシャスには
関わらないほうがいいよ
But I know saying that is useless.
って言っても無駄だよね
Sorry.
（スパイク）悪いな
You've never listened to what others say.
（アニー）あんた 昔っから
人の言うことは聞かないよね
おまけに見えっ張りの意地っ張り
On top of it, you're a stubborn showoff!
It can't hurt you to listen to your elders once in a while...
たまにゃ
年寄りの言うこと聞いたって―
罰(ばち)は当たんないよ
About Mao...
マオはね
あんたがいなくなってから
随分 人に捜させていたんだよ
He had a lot of people looking for you after you were gone.
He said that you still had to be alive...
“きっと生きてるはずだ”って
You're finally back, but Mao is...
せっかく あんたが
戻ってきたっていうのに―
マオときたら…
（スパイク）もうよせ
Stop it already.
This is for Mao!
こいつはマオの分だよ
マオの分なら俺がもらっとく
I'll take that one for Mao.
What are you up to now... to need something like THAT?
どうしようってんだ？
そんなもん持ち出して
Where's the broad?
女は？
She lost sanity looking at the bounty figure and took off.
賞金に目がくらんで
飛び出していきやがった
Right now she's probably somewhere, screwing up.
今頃 どこぞで
なんぞ しくじってるだろうよ
I see.
（スパイク）なるほど
言っとくけどな
マオの賞金は手に入らねえぞ
I'll tell you something.  You won't get the bounty for Mao.
He's already dead.  He was killed.
もう死んでる　殺されたんだ
Internal discord.  Do you understand?
仲間割れでな
分かってんのか？
こいつは わなだ　間違いねえ
This is a trap!  I'm sure of it!
Yeah.  I know all that.
ああ　全部 知ってる
You know?!
知ってるだと？
Then what, you're Mao's?
まさかお前 マオの…
I owe him one from before...
昔 世話になった
教えてやるよ スパイク
I'll tell you something, Spike.
（スパイク）あ？
この腕はな 俺がいきがって
先走った揚げ句の代償だ
This arm.  It's the price I paid for being over-spirited...
...and running ahead of the game.  You understand?
分かるか？
I don't wanna go, either.
（スパイク）
俺だって行きたかねえよ
だったら…
Then...
渡世の仁義ってやつさ
Let's just say, duties of the life I live.
へへー 捕まってしまいました
Tee hee.  I've been caught.
おま…
You...
"Come to the place we specify."
（フェイ）
“これから指定する場所に来い”
“さもないと私の命はないぞ”
だそうでーす
Otherwise, my life is over.  So they say.
えーと時間はですね
Let's see... the time to meet is...
It's because you did as you please.
（ジェット）
勝手なことをするからだ
あー 冷たい　仲間じゃない
You're being cold.  We're comrades, remember?
自業自得だ
自分で落とし前をつけるんだな
You reap what you sow.  Take care of it all yourself.
（フェイ）ああ ね ちょっと…
Hey, wait!
どこだ？
Where is it?
えっ？ 本当に来てくれるの？
You're really gonna come?
安心しな
お前を助けに行くわけじゃない
Don't worry.  I'm not going there to save you.
Spike!
（ジェット）スパイク！
Angels that are forced from heaven have to become demons.
（ビシャス）
天国を追い出された天使は
悪魔になるしかないんだ
そうだろ？ スパイク
Isn't that right, Spike?
フッ 俺は ただ
覚めない夢を見てるだけさ
I'm only watching a dream that I never awakened from.
I'll wake you up right now.
（ビシャス）今 覚めさせてやる
Don't be so anxious, Vicious.
（スパイク）慌てるなよ ビシャス
久しぶりの再会だぜ
It's our first meeting in a while, right?
A plea for your life?
（ビシャス）命乞いか
Hardly.
（スパイク）まさか　そんなまねが
通じる お前じゃないだろ
Something like that doesn't work on you, remember?
恩人だって
さっさと殺しちまうんだからな
After all, you even kill those who've saved your life.
やつは牙をなくした獣だ
だから死んだのさ
He was a beast who lost his fangs.  That's why he's dead.
The same goes for you.
お前も同じだ
（フェイ）ああっ
さあ 銃を捨ててもらおうか
Now, we want you to drop your gun.
～
What's wrong?  If you don't hurry...
どうした？ 早くしないと…
殺す気？
Are you tryin' to kill me?
Oh man, what the hell have I done...
あー なんてこった
Yeah?
あいよ
（フェイ）よかった ジェット
スパイクが…
Thank God!  Jet?  Spike is...
Not my problem!
知らん！
God dammit!
（ジェット）ええい くそっ
（荒い息）
スパイク
Spike.
今 自分がどんな顔をしているか
分かるか？
Do you know what your face looks like right now?
What?
何？
The same blood runs in you and me.
（ビシャス）お前には
俺と同じ血が流れている
The blood of a beast who wanders, desiring the blood of others.
別の血を求め さまよう獣の血だ
I've bled all of that blood away.
（スパイク）
そんな血は もう流し尽くしたさ
ならば なぜ生きている？
Then why are you still alive?!
～
（ジュリアの鼻歌）
Just like that...
（スパイク）そのまま歌ってくれ
...sing for me.
（フェイの鼻歌）
やっと起きた　寝過ぎよ ３日も
Oh, you're finally up.
You've slept too much.  It's been three days.
What?  I was worried about you.  You have to be thankful to me!
何よ 心配してやったんだから
ありがたく思いなさいよ？
（スパイク）音痴
Tone-deaf.
（スパイクの悲鳴）
やれやれ
Oh, well...
Too much time has passed by...
Aishiteta to nageku niwa
...to lament that we were deeply in love.
Amarinimo toki wa sugite shimatta
The wind keeps blowing, while my heart...
Mada kokoro no hokorobi wo
...cannot heal all the tears in it.
lyasenu mama kaze ga fuiteru
Someone, cry for me with parched eyes.
Kawaita hitomi de dareka naite kure
The real folk blues.
The real folk blues
I only want to know what true sadness is.
Honto no kanashimi ga shiritai dake
Sitting in muddy water...
Doro no kawa ni tsukatta
...isn't such a bad life...
Jinsei mo waruku wa nai
...if it ends after the first time...
Ichido kiri de owaru nara
～
（スパイク）しかし なんだな
世知辛い世の中になったもんだな
But you know what?  What a tough world we live in nowadays...
（ジェット）何の話だ？
What are you talking about?
This guy, that guy...  They're all trying to put a lid on something that stinks.
（スパイク）どいつも こいつも
臭いものにふたしてるだけだろ
Yeah.
なあ そんなことでいいのか？
Can we let things go on like that?
I'm asking you, what ARE you talking about?
（ジェット）だから何の話だよ？
World affairs, man!  World affairs!
（スパイク）世の中だよ 世の中
With all these lids about, the world'll be buried in lids!
そんなに ふたばっかりしてちゃ
世間は ふたで埋まっちまうぜ
I don't really get it...
（ジェット）よく分からんなあ
（スパイク）そんなことじゃ
真実は見えないんだよ
With stuff like that, you can't see the truth!
Truth, huh?
（ジェット）真実ねえ
So lids like that...  I'll crush them all away!
（スパイク）だから そんなふたは
俺がみんな たたき割ってやる
次回「悪魔を憐(あわ)れむ歌」
Next Episode: "Sympathy for the Devil".
That sounds... smelly.
（ジェット）臭そうだな